Guru Ranganathan

IOS Developer

Address: Chennai, 600053 Phone: +91 996 288 0626 E-mail: gurugovindaprasad@gmail.com

iOS Developer with more than 4 years of experience leading the creation of complex, user-focused software application at the highest level of quality and efficiency. Adept at verifying compliance with both App Store policies and design best practices. Creates efficient, reliable frameworks to produce profitable applications.

Skills

Swift

Objective-C

UIKit Framework

RESTful APIs

Cocoa Touch

Communication

Work History

Computer Programmer

Mar 2017 - Dec 2019

B Creative, Kuwait City, Kuwait

- Applied Apple's Swift development language to code native apps for iOS platform which made the product faster and removed existing memory management issues.
- Followed Apple's Human Interface guidelines to create products which in turn increased the app store approval rate.
- Worked with stakeholders such as CEO and Chairman to find collaborative ways to deliver business
 value for all parties.
- Applied Agile software development methodology to elevate final products and streamline development efforts.
- Researched and selected APIs for integration into development projects to reduce decelopment time and to improve the stability of the product.
- Worked closely with UI/UX designer and other development teams to analyze potential system solution based on evloving product requirements.

Software Developer

Nov 2014 - Jul 2016

MacAppStudio, Chennai, TamilNadu

 Complied with all Apple App Store guidelines to provide rapid approval and deployment to retail channels.

- Translated basic design plans into full iOS app frameworks, delegating project components to appropriate team members which multiplied the productivity of the team.
- Designed user experience frameworks applicable to multiple screen sizes, including both iPad and iPhone to enhance overall adoption rates.
- Collaborated with cross functional development teams members to deliver high availability solutions for critical applications.
- Collaborated with CTO to brainstorm new application concepts based on available development assets and historical successes to boost the company's revenue.

Projects

Beep - Cars Community:

beep Messenger is a FREE CARS LOVERS messaging app available for iPhone and other smartphones. We created beep to Simplify the Connect between any car owners in the WORLD! and to build the World first Car Owners Social Network Experience.

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/beep-cars-community/id1219747768

Znap:

Znap - UAE's Cashback & Rewards App

Znap gives you Cash rewards to shop and interact with Brands and Products that you already buy. It is one of the easiest ways to save money on the Brands & Products you love.

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/znap-cash-back-app/id1013991450

Education

Bachelor of Engineering: Electronics and Instrumentation

Sep 2010 - May 2014

Velammal Engineering College - Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Additional Information

Willing to relocate